So this code over here gets the job done,
这就是对应代码
this HTML translates to a nice looking read beam.
HTML 可以转化为美观的 readme
But we can do this in less code if we do this in markdown.
markdown 能用更少的代码做同样的事
So let's start translating this so that we get the same results.
让我们着手去做
Right off the bat, we can see that we've got an H1 and two H2s over here.
首先我们看到一个 H1 两个 H2 标签
These can be translated pretty easily using the hash syntax in markdown.
直接在 markdown 中使用 # 进行标记即可
Remember that the number of hashes indicates
注意 # 的不同数量对应着
which H tag you're going to be using from H1 all the way to H6.
H1 到 H6 六种标签尺寸
Next we can see that we've got two paragraphs here.
之后是两个段落
In markdown, these P tags for the paragraphs are not necessary so
在 markdown 中我们无需使用 P 标签
we can go ahead and take those out.
去掉它们即可
Next we've got the strong tag along with the M tag
之后是 strong 和 em 标签
which should look familiar from the last exercise.
我们在之前练习中接触过
Strong makes our text bold, M makes our texts italics.
strong 将字体加粗 em 标记斜体
So, we can go ahead and rewrite those and we've got now the last two sections,
重写这两部分 还剩最后两部分要处理
our list and our code blocks.
列表和代码块
This is going to be where mark down really going to come in handy And
这是充分显示 markdown 方便性的地方
save us a lot of code.
能省去大量编码工作
We've got our unordered list here.
我们的无序列表在这里
And you can see we have the UL tag and
你可以看到 UL 标签
then an LI tag for each one of those list items.
跟着对应每一个列表元素的 LI 标签
In mark down, we just need a single asterisk for each one of those list
在 markdown 中我们只要在每个列表元素前
items, and it's going to automatically know that this is a list.
放置一个星号 系统能自动识别这是一个列表
And you can see that our read me still looks exactly the same.
同时我们的 readme 外观未变
Next we can take this anchor tag here and shorten that a bit.
之后来替换 a 标签并缩短一下这里
We're going to use the bracket syntax to indict the text that we want in our link
在方括号中放置链接文本
and then parenthesis to indicate our path.
圆括号中写上对应路径
Here at the bottom we see the pre-code combination here
最底下是 pre-code 标签组合
which will generate this code block.
用于标识代码块
This may not be code that you're super familiar with.
你现在可能对它还不熟悉
But when you are writing code like this it comes in handy very often.
但当你编写这样的代码时 它往往很方便
But this can be rewritten easily using the three back ticks.
这部分可以用反引号替代
So we'll use three back ticks to indicate the start of our code block,
用三个反引号代表代码块的开始
another three to indicate the end of our code block.
另外三个反引号代表代码块的结束
So as you can see, this mark down translates to the same read me
可以看到这里的 markdown 效果
that the HTML we had written did.
也与 HTML 页面一致
But it does it in a way that is much more readable.
同时更具可读性
Even if we didn't have this mark down file being generated here on the right.
即使没有生成最终 md 文件
We could still look through this mark down file and more or less understand
我们也可以直接阅读 markdown 代码
what's going on and it took us considerably less code to get there.
理解文档内容 同时大大减少代码量